expertise.com 2016-12-06

# Privacy Policy - Expertise

**Last Updated:  June 16th, 2015**

Welcome to Expertise! This Privacy Policy explains how information about you is collected, used and disclosed by Expertise LLC (“Expertise,” “we” or “us”) when you access or use our websites, widgets and other online products and services (collectively, the “Services”) or when you otherwise interact with us. This Privacy Policy does not, however, describe the practices of third parties that may collect information from you when you interact with them, including professionals (referred to as “Experts”). Any information provided directly to an Expert is treated in accordance with that Expert’s privacy practices and we encourage you to ask the Expert for information about their practices before providing any information to them.

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make changes, we will notify you by revising the date at the top of the policy and, in some cases, we may provide you with additional notice (such as adding a statement to our website’s homepage or sending you a notification). We encourage you to review the Privacy Policy whenever you access the Services or otherwise interact with us to stay informed about our information practices and the ways you can help protect your privacy.

## Collection of Information

**Information You Provide to Us**

We collect information you provide directly to us. For example, we collect information when you: create an account or profile; submit a project request; use the interactive areas and features of the Services; participate in a contest, promotion or survey; sign up for our mailing list; make a purchase; apply for a job; communicate with us via third party social media sites; request customer support or otherwise communicate with us.

When you use our Services to find an Expert, we collect information from you, such as your name, email address, zip code, phone number, information about your project and the type of Expert you are looking for and any additional information you choose to provide. We may also collect information from you in connection with reviews you submit and any communications you have with Experts through the Services.

If you use the Services as an Expert, we collect information about you and your company, including but not limited to your name, company name, address, email address, phone number, website URL, areas of expertise, prior work experience, education, qualifications, featured projects, photos, communications you have with other users through the Services and any other information you choose to provide.

**Information We Collect Automatically When You Use the Services**

When you access or use our Services, we automatically collect information about you, including:

  * **Log Information:** We collect log information about your use of the Services, including the type of browser you use, access times, pages viewed, your IP address and the page you visited before navigating to our Services.
  * **Information Collected by Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies:** We may use cookies, web beacons, and other tracking technologies to collect information about you and your interaction with our Services, including information about your browsing behavior, purchase behavior and other engagement with our Services. Cookies are small data files stored on your hard drive or in device memory that help us improve our Services and your experience. Web beacons are electronic images that may be used in our Services or emails and help deliver cookies, count visits and understand usage and campaign effectiveness. We use this information in one or more of the ways described in the “Use of Information” section below. For more information about cookies, and how to disable them, please see “Your Choices” below.

**Information We Collect From Other Sources**

We may also obtain information from other sources and combine that with information we collect through our Services.   For example, if you create or log into your account through a social media platform, we will have access to certain information from that platform, such as your name, account information and friends lists, in accordance with the authorization procedures determined by such social media site. We may also collect information about Experts from publicly available sources and combine that with information we collect directly through our Services.

## Use of Information

We may use information about you for various purposes, including to:

  * Provide, maintain and improve our Services and provide you with relevant information and connections;
  * Send you technical notices, updates, security alerts and support and administrative messages;
  * Respond to your comments, questions and requests and provide customer service;
  * Communicate with you about products, services, offers, promotions, rewards and events offered by us and others, and provide news and information we think will be of interest to you;
  * Monitor and analyze trends, usage and activities in connection with our Services;
  * Personalize and improve the Services and provide advertisements, content or features that match user profiles or interests;
  * Process and deliver contest or sweepstakes entries and prizes;
  * Link or combine with information we get from others to help understand your needs and provide you with better service; and
  * Carry out any other purpose for which the information was collected.

We are based in the United States and the information we collect is governed by U.S. law. By accessing or using the Services or otherwise providing information to us, you consent to the processing and transfer of information in and to the U.S.

## Sharing of Information

We may share information about you as follows or as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy:

  * With vendors, consultants and other service providers who need access to such information to complete transactions or perform services on our behalf;
  * When you create a profile or otherwise participate in the interactive areas of our Services, certain information about you may be displayed publicly on our Services, such as your profile information, business information, projects, posts, reviews, and other information you choose to provide;
  * In response to a request for information if we believe disclosure is in accordance with, or required by, any applicable law, regulation or legal process;
  * If we believe your actions are inconsistent with our user agreements or policies, or to protect the rights, property and safety of Expertise or others;
  * In connection with, or during negotiations of, any merger, sale of company assets, financing or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by another company;
  * With your consent or at your direction, including with Experts if you opt into this type of sharing.

We may also share aggregated or de-identified information, which cannot reasonably be used to identify you.

## Social Sharing Features

The Services may offer social sharing features and other integrated tools (such as the Facebook “Like” button), which let you share actions you take on our Services with other media, and vice versa. Your use of such features enables the sharing of information with your friends or the public, depending on the settings you establish with the entity that provides the social sharing feature. For more information about the purpose and scope of data collection and processing in connection with social sharing features, please visit the privacy policies of the entities that provide these features.

## Advertising and Analytics Services Provided by Others

We may allow others to provide analytics services and serve advertisements on our behalf across the Internet and in applications. These entities may use cookies, web beacons, device identifiers and other technologies to collect information about your use of the Services and other websites and applications, including your IP address, web browser, mobile network information, pages viewed, time spent on pages or in apps, links clicked and conversion information. This information may be used by us and others to, among other things, analyze and track data, determine the popularity of certain content, deliver advertising and content targeted to your interests on our Services and other websites and better understand your online activity. For more information about interest-based ads, or to opt out of having your web browsing information used for behavioral advertising purposes, please visit [www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices).We may also work with third parties to serve ads to you as part of a customized campaign on other websites or platforms. To opt out of having information about you used in this way, please email us at legal@expertise.com.

## Security

Expertise takes reasonable measures to help protect information about you from loss, theft, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction.

## Your Choices

**Account Information**

You may update, correct or delete information about you at any time by logging into your online account. If you wish to deactivate your account, you may do so by logging into your account and selecting that option under Account Settings, but note that we may retain certain information as required by law or for legitimate business purposes. We may also retain cached or archived copies of information about you for a certain period of time.

**Cookies**

Most web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove or reject browser cookies. Please note that if you choose to remove or reject cookies, this could affect the availability and functionality of our Services.

**Promotional Communications**

You may opt out of receiving promotional communications from us by following the instructions in those communications. If you opt out, we may still send you non-promotional communications, such as those about your account or our ongoing business relations.

**Your California Privacy Rights**

California law permits residents of California to request certain details about how their information is shared with third parties for direct marketing purposes. However, please note that under the law, a business is not required to provide this information if it permits California residents to opt into, or opt out of, this type of sharing. Expertise qualifies for this alternative option. As described above, we will not share information about you with third parties for their direct marketing purposes without your consent. In addition, you can request that we stop future disclosures of your information for direct marketing purposes by contacting us at legal@expertise.com.

## Contact Us

If you have any questions, comments, or concerns about this Privacy Policy or our privacy practices, please contact us at: legal@expertise.com.
